<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>OpenClaw</title>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.12</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:17:54 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>9500</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.12</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.12</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>CLI: add <code>openclaw logs --local-time</code> to display log timestamps in local timezone. (#13818) Thanks @xialonglee.</li>
<li>Telegram: render blockquotes as native <code><blockquote></code> tags instead of stripping them. (#14608)</li>
<li>Config: avoid redacting <code>maxTokens</code>-like fields during config snapshot redaction, preventing round-trip validation failures in <code>/config</code>. (#14006) Thanks @constansino.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Breaking</h3>
<ul>
<li>Hooks: <code>POST /hooks/agent</code> now rejects payload <code>sessionKey</code> overrides by default. To keep fixed hook context, set <code>hooks.defaultSessionKey</code> (recommended with <code>hooks.allowedSessionKeyPrefixes: ["hook:"]</code>). If you need legacy behavior, explicitly set <code>hooks.allowRequestSessionKey: true</code>. Thanks @alpernae for reporting.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Gateway/OpenResponses: harden URL-based <code>input_file</code>/<code>input_image</code> handling with explicit SSRF deny policy, hostname allowlists (<code>files.urlAllowlist</code> / <code>images.urlAllowlist</code>), per-request URL input caps (<code>maxUrlParts</code>), blocked-fetch audit logging, and regression coverage/docs updates.</li>
<li>Security: fix unauthenticated Nostr profile API remote config tampering. (#13719) Thanks @coygeek.</li>
<li>Security: remove bundled soul-evil hook. (#14757) Thanks @Imccccc.</li>
<li>Security/Audit: add hook session-routing hardening checks (<code>hooks.defaultSessionKey</code>, <code>hooks.allowRequestSessionKey</code>, and prefix allowlists), and warn when HTTP API endpoints allow explicit session-key routing.</li>
<li>Security/Sandbox: confine mirrored skill sync destinations to the sandbox <code>skills/</code> root and stop using frontmatter-controlled skill names as filesystem destination paths. Thanks @1seal.</li>
<li>Security/Web tools: treat browser/web content as untrusted by default (wrapped outputs for browser snapshot/tabs/console and structured external-content metadata for web tools), and strip <code>toolResult.details</code> from model-facing transcript/compaction inputs to reduce prompt-injection replay risk.</li>
<li>Security/Hooks: harden webhook and device token verification with shared constant-time secret comparison, and add per-client auth-failure throttling for hook endpoints (<code>429</code> + <code>Retry-After</code>). Thanks @akhmittra.</li>
<li>Security/Browser: require auth for loopback browser control HTTP routes, auto-generate <code>gateway.auth.token</code> when browser control starts without auth, and add a security-audit check for unauthenticated browser control. Thanks @tcusolle.</li>
<li>Sessions/Gateway: harden transcript path resolution and reject unsafe session IDs/file paths so session operations stay within agent sessions directories. Thanks @akhmittra.</li>
<li>Gateway: raise WS payload/buffer limits so 5,000,000-byte image attachments work reliably. (#14486) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Logging/CLI: use local timezone timestamps for console prefixing, and include <code>±HH:MM</code> offsets when using <code>openclaw logs --local-time</code> to avoid ambiguity. (#14771) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Gateway: drain active turns before restart to prevent message loss. (#13931) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Gateway: auto-generate auth token during install to prevent launchd restart loops. (#13813) Thanks @cathrynlavery.</li>
<li>Gateway: prevent <code>undefined</code>/missing token in auth config. (#13809) Thanks @asklee-klawd.</li>
<li>Gateway: handle async <code>EPIPE</code> on stdout/stderr during shutdown. (#13414) Thanks @keshav55.</li>
<li>Gateway/Control UI: resolve missing dashboard assets when <code>openclaw</code> is installed globally via symlink-based Node managers (nvm/fnm/n/Homebrew). (#14919) Thanks @aynorica.</li>
<li>Cron: use requested <code>agentId</code> for isolated job auth resolution. (#13983) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent cron jobs from skipping execution when <code>nextRunAtMs</code> advances. (#14068) Thanks @WalterSumbon.</li>
<li>Cron: pass <code>agentId</code> to <code>runHeartbeatOnce</code> for main-session jobs. (#14140) Thanks @ishikawa-pro.</li>
<li>Cron: re-arm timers when <code>onTimer</code> fires while a job is still executing. (#14233) Thanks @tomron87.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent duplicate fires when multiple jobs trigger simultaneously. (#14256) Thanks @xinhuagu.</li>
<li>Cron: isolate scheduler errors so one bad job does not break all jobs. (#14385) Thanks @MarvinDontPanic.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent one-shot <code>at</code> jobs from re-firing on restart after skipped/errored runs. (#13878) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Heartbeat: prevent scheduler stalls on unexpected run errors and avoid immediate rerun loops after <code>requests-in-flight</code> skips. (#14901) Thanks @joeykrug.</li>
<li>Cron: honor stored session model overrides for isolated-agent runs while preserving <code>hooks.gmail.model</code> precedence for Gmail hook sessions. (#14983) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Logging/Browser: fall back to <code>os.tmpdir()/openclaw</code> for default log, browser trace, and browser download temp paths when <code>/tmp/openclaw</code> is unavailable.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: convert Markdown bold/strikethrough to WhatsApp formatting. (#14285) Thanks @Raikan10.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: allow media-only sends and normalize leading blank payloads. (#14408) Thanks @karimnaguib.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: default MIME type for voice messages when Baileys omits it. (#14444) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Telegram: handle no-text message in model picker editMessageText. (#14397) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Telegram: surface REACTION_INVALID as non-fatal warning. (#14340) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>BlueBubbles: fix webhook auth bypass via loopback proxy trust. (#13787) Thanks @coygeek.</li>
<li>Slack: change default replyToMode from "off" to "all". (#14364) Thanks @nm-de.</li>
<li>Slack: detect control commands when channel messages start with bot mention prefixes (for example, <code>@Bot /new</code>). (#14142) Thanks @beefiker.</li>
<li>Signal: enforce E.164 validation for the Signal bot account prompt so mistyped numbers are caught early. (#15063) Thanks @Duartemartins.</li>
<li>Discord: process DM reactions instead of silently dropping them. (#10418) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Discord: respect replyToMode in threads. (#11062) Thanks @cordx56.</li>
<li>Heartbeat: filter noise-only system events so scheduled reminder notifications do not fire when cron runs carry only heartbeat markers. (#13317) Thanks @pvtclawn.</li>
<li>Signal: render mention placeholders as <code>@uuid</code>/<code>@phone</code> so mention gating and Clawdbot targeting work. (#2013) Thanks @alexgleason.</li>
<li>Discord: omit empty content fields for media-only messages while preserving caption whitespace. (#9507) Thanks @leszekszpunar.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Providers: add Z.AI endpoint-specific auth choices (<code>zai-coding-global</code>, <code>zai-coding-cn</code>, <code>zai-global</code>, <code>zai-cn</code>) and expand default Z.AI model wiring. (#13456) Thanks @tomsun28.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Providers: update MiniMax API default/recommended models from M2.1 to M2.5, add M2.5/M2.5-Lightning model entries, and include <code>minimax-m2.5</code> in modern model filtering. (#14865) Thanks @adao-max.</li>
<li>Ollama: use configured <code>models.providers.ollama.baseUrl</code> for model discovery and normalize <code>/v1</code> endpoints to the native Ollama API root. (#14131) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Voice Call: pass Twilio stream auth token via <code><Parameter></code> instead of query string. (#14029) Thanks @mcwigglesmcgee.</li>
<li>Feishu: pass <code>Buffer</code> directly to the Feishu SDK upload APIs instead of <code>Readable.from(...)</code> to avoid form-data upload failures. (#10345) Thanks @youngerstyle.</li>
<li>Feishu: trigger mention-gated group handling only when the bot itself is mentioned (not just any mention). (#11088) Thanks @openperf.</li>
<li>Feishu: probe status uses the resolved account context for multi-account credential checks. (#11233) Thanks @onevcat.</li>
<li>Feishu DocX: preserve top-level converted block order using <code>firstLevelBlockIds</code> when writing/appending documents. (#13994) Thanks @Cynosure159.</li>
<li>Feishu plugin packaging: remove <code>workspace:*</code> <code>openclaw</code> dependency from <code>extensions/feishu</code> and sync lockfile for install compatibility. (#14423) Thanks @jackcooper2015.</li>
<li>CLI/Wizard: exit with code 1 when <code>configure</code>, <code>agents add</code>, or interactive <code>onboard</code> wizards are canceled, so <code>set -e</code> automation stops correctly. (#14156) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Media: strip <code>MEDIA:</code> lines with local paths instead of leaking as visible text. (#14399) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Config/Cron: exclude <code>maxTokens</code> from config redaction and honor <code>deleteAfterRun</code> on skipped cron jobs. (#13342) Thanks @niceysam.</li>
<li>Config: ignore <code>meta</code> field changes in config file watcher. (#13460) Thanks @brandonwise.</li>
<li>Cron: use requested <code>agentId</code> for isolated job auth resolution. (#13983) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Cron: pass <code>agentId</code> to <code>runHeartbeatOnce</code> for main-session jobs. (#14140) Thanks @ishikawa-pro.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent cron jobs from skipping execution when <code>nextRunAtMs</code> advances. (#14068) Thanks @WalterSumbon.</li>
<li>Cron: re-arm timers when <code>onTimer</code> fires while a job is still executing. (#14233) Thanks @tomron87.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent duplicate fires when multiple jobs trigger simultaneously. (#14256) Thanks @xinhuagu.</li>
<li>Cron: isolate scheduler errors so one bad job does not break all jobs. (#14385) Thanks @MarvinDontPanic.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent one-shot <code>at</code> jobs from re-firing on restart after skipped/errored runs. (#13878) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Daemon: suppress <code>EPIPE</code> error when restarting LaunchAgent. (#14343) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Antigravity: add opus 4.6 forward-compat model and bypass thinking signature sanitization. (#14218) Thanks @jg-noncelogic.</li>
<li>Agents: prevent file descriptor leaks in child process cleanup. (#13565) Thanks @KyleChen26.</li>
<li>Agents: prevent double compaction caused by cache TTL bypassing guard. (#13514) Thanks @taw0002.</li>
<li>Agents: use last API call's cache tokens for context display instead of accumulated sum. (#13805) Thanks @akari-musubi.</li>
<li>Agents: keep followup-runner session <code>totalTokens</code> aligned with post-compaction context by using last-call usage and shared token-accounting logic. (#14979) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Hooks/Plugins: wire 9 previously unwired plugin lifecycle hooks into core runtime paths (session, compaction, gateway, and outbound message hooks). (#14882) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Hooks/Tools: dispatch <code>before_tool_call</code> and <code>after_tool_call</code> hooks from both tool execution paths with rebased conflict fixes. (#15012) Thanks @Patrick-Barletta, @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Discord: allow channel-edit to archive/lock threads and set auto-archive duration. (#5542) Thanks @stumct.</li>
<li>Discord tests: use a partial @buape/carbon mock in slash command coverage. (#13262) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Tests: update thread ID handling in Slack message collection tests. (#14108) Thanks @swizzmagik.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.12/OpenClaw-2026.2.12.zip" length="22877692" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="TGylTM4/7Lab+qp1nuPeOAmEVV1WkafXUPub8ws0z/0mYfbVygRuiev+u3zdPjQWhLnGYTgRgKVyW+kB2+Q2BQ=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.9</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:23:25 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>9194</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.9</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.9</h2>
<h3>Added</h3>
<ul>
<li>iOS: alpha node app + setup-code onboarding. (#11756) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Channels: comprehensive BlueBubbles and channel cleanup. (#11093) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Plugins: device pairing + phone control plugins (Telegram <code>/pair</code>, iOS/Android node controls). (#11755) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Tools: add Grok (xAI) as a <code>web_search</code> provider. (#12419) Thanks @tmchow.</li>
<li>Gateway: add agent management RPC methods for the web UI (<code>agents.create</code>, <code>agents.update</code>, <code>agents.delete</code>). (#11045) Thanks @advaitpaliwal.</li>
<li>Web UI: show a Compaction divider in chat history. (#11341) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Agents: include runtime shell in agent envelopes. (#1835) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Paths: add <code>OPENCLAW_HOME</code> for overriding the home directory used by internal path resolution. (#12091) Thanks @sebslight.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Telegram: harden quote parsing; preserve quote context; avoid QUOTE_TEXT_INVALID; avoid nested reply quote misclassification. (#12156) Thanks @rybnikov.</li>
<li>Telegram: recover proactive sends when stale topic thread IDs are used by retrying without <code>message_thread_id</code>. (#11620)</li>
<li>Telegram: render markdown spoilers with <code><tg-spoiler></code> HTML tags. (#11543) Thanks @ezhikkk.</li>
<li>Telegram: truncate command registration to 100 entries to avoid <code>BOT_COMMANDS_TOO_MUCH</code> failures on startup. (#12356) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Telegram: match DM <code>allowFrom</code> against sender user id (fallback to chat id) and clarify pairing logs. (#12779) Thanks @liuxiaopai-ai.</li>
<li>Onboarding: QuickStart now auto-installs shell completion (prompt only in Manual).</li>
<li>Auth: strip embedded line breaks from pasted API keys and tokens before storing/resolving credentials.</li>
<li>Web UI: make chat refresh smoothly scroll to the latest messages and suppress new-messages badge flash during manual refresh.</li>
<li>Tools/web_search: include provider-specific settings in the web search cache key, and pass <code>inlineCitations</code> for Grok. (#12419) Thanks @tmchow.</li>
<li>Tools/web_search: normalize direct Perplexity model IDs while keeping OpenRouter model IDs unchanged. (#12795) Thanks @cdorsey.</li>
<li>Model failover: treat HTTP 400 errors as failover-eligible, enabling automatic model fallback. (#1879) Thanks @orenyomtov.</li>
<li>Errors: prevent false positive context overflow detection when conversation mentions "context overflow" topic. (#2078) Thanks @sbking.</li>
<li>Gateway: no more post-compaction amnesia; injected transcript writes now preserve Pi session <code>parentId</code> chain so agents can remember again. (#12283) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Gateway: fix multi-agent sessions.usage discovery. (#11523) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Agents: recover from context overflow caused by oversized tool results (pre-emptive capping + fallback truncation). (#11579) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Subagents/compaction: stabilize announce timing and preserve compaction metrics across retries. (#11664) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Cron: share isolated announce flow and harden scheduling/delivery reliability. (#11641) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Cron tool: recover flat params when LLM omits the <code>job</code> wrapper for add requests. (#12124) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Gateway/CLI: when <code>gateway.bind=lan</code>, use a LAN IP for probe URLs and Control UI links. (#11448) Thanks @AnonO6.</li>
<li>Hooks: fix bundled hooks broken since 2026.2.2 (tsdown migration). (#9295) Thanks @patrickshao.</li>
<li>Routing: refresh bindings per message by loading config at route resolution so binding changes apply without restart. (#11372) Thanks @juanpablodlc.</li>
<li>Exec approvals: render forwarded commands in monospace for safer approval scanning. (#11937) Thanks @sebslight.</li>
<li>Config: clamp <code>maxTokens</code> to <code>contextWindow</code> to prevent invalid model configs. (#5516) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Thinking: allow xhigh for <code>github-copilot/gpt-5.2-codex</code> and <code>github-copilot/gpt-5.2</code>. (#11646) Thanks @LatencyTDH.</li>
<li>Discord: support forum/media thread-create starter messages, wire <code>message thread create --message</code>, and harden routing. (#10062) Thanks @jarvis89757.</li>
<li>Paths: structurally resolve <code>OPENCLAW_HOME</code>-derived home paths and fix Windows drive-letter handling in tool meta shortening. (#12125) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Memory: set Voyage embeddings <code>input_type</code> for improved retrieval. (#10818) Thanks @mcinteerj.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: reuse default model cache across agents instead of re-downloading per agent. (#12114) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Media understanding: recognize <code>.caf</code> audio attachments for transcription. (#10982) Thanks @succ985.</li>
<li>State dir: honor <code>OPENCLAW_STATE_DIR</code> for default device identity and canvas storage paths. (#4824) Thanks @kossoy.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.9/OpenClaw-2026.2.9.zip" length="22872529" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="zvgwqlgqI7J5Gsi9VSULIQTMKqLiGE5ulC6NnRLKtOPphQsHZVdYSWm0E90+Yq8mG4lpsvbxQOSSPxpl43QTAw=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.3</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:47:10 -0800</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>8900</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.3</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.3</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Telegram: remove last <code>@ts-nocheck</code> from <code>bot-handlers.ts</code>, use Grammy types directly, deduplicate <code>StickerMetadata</code>. Zero <code>@ts-nocheck</code> remaining in <code>src/telegram/</code>. (#9206)</li>
<li>Telegram: remove <code>@ts-nocheck</code> from <code>bot-message.ts</code>, type deps via <code>Omit<BuildTelegramMessageContextParams></code>, widen <code>allMedia</code> to <code>TelegramMediaRef[]</code>. (#9180)</li>
<li>Telegram: remove <code>@ts-nocheck</code> from <code>bot.ts</code>, fix duplicate <code>bot.catch</code> error handler (Grammy overrides), remove dead reaction <code>message_thread_id</code> routing, harden sticker cache guard. (#9077)</li>
<li>Onboarding: add Cloudflare AI Gateway provider setup and docs. (#7914) Thanks @roerohan.</li>
<li>Onboarding: add Moonshot (.cn) auth choice and keep the China base URL when preserving defaults. (#7180) Thanks @waynelwz.</li>
<li>Docs: clarify tmux send-keys for TUI by splitting text and Enter. (#7737) Thanks @Wangnov.</li>
<li>Docs: mirror the landing page revamp for zh-CN (features, quickstart, docs directory, network model, credits). (#8994) Thanks @joshp123.</li>
<li>Messages: add per-channel and per-account responsePrefix overrides across channels. (#9001) Thanks @mudrii.</li>
<li>Cron: add announce delivery mode for isolated jobs (CLI + Control UI) and delivery mode config.</li>
<li>Cron: default isolated jobs to announce delivery; accept ISO 8601 <code>schedule.at</code> in tool inputs.</li>
<li>Cron: hard-migrate isolated jobs to announce/none delivery; drop legacy post-to-main/payload delivery fields and <code>atMs</code> inputs.</li>
<li>Cron: delete one-shot jobs after success by default; add <code>--keep-after-run</code> for CLI.</li>
<li>Cron: suppress messaging tools during announce delivery so summaries post consistently.</li>
<li>Cron: avoid duplicate deliveries when isolated runs send messages directly.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Heartbeat: allow explicit accountId routing for multi-account channels. (#8702) Thanks @lsh411.</li>
<li>TUI/Gateway: handle non-streaming finals, refresh history for non-local chat runs, and avoid event gap warnings for targeted tool streams. (#8432) Thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Shell completion: auto-detect and migrate slow dynamic patterns to cached files for faster terminal startup; add completion health checks to doctor/update/onboard.</li>
<li>Telegram: honor session model overrides in inline model selection. (#8193) Thanks @gildo.</li>
<li>Web UI: fix agent model selection saves for default/non-default agents and wrap long workspace paths. Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Web UI: resolve header logo path when <code>gateway.controlUi.basePath</code> is set. (#7178) Thanks @Yeom-JinHo.</li>
<li>Web UI: apply button styling to the new-messages indicator.</li>
<li>Security: keep untrusted channel metadata out of system prompts (Slack/Discord). Thanks @KonstantinMirin.</li>
<li>Security: enforce sandboxed media paths for message tool attachments. (#9182) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Security: require explicit credentials for gateway URL overrides to prevent credential leakage. (#8113) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Security: gate <code>whatsapp_login</code> tool to owner senders and default-deny non-owner contexts. (#8768) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Voice call: harden webhook verification with host allowlists/proxy trust and keep ngrok loopback bypass.</li>
<li>Voice call: add regression coverage for anonymous inbound caller IDs with allowlist policy. (#8104) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Cron: accept epoch timestamps and 0ms durations in CLI <code>--at</code> parsing.</li>
<li>Cron: reload store data when the store file is recreated or mtime changes.</li>
<li>Cron: deliver announce runs directly, honor delivery mode, and respect wakeMode for summaries. (#8540) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Telegram: include forward_from_chat metadata in forwarded messages and harden cron delivery target checks. (#8392) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
<li>macOS: fix cron payload summary rendering and ISO 8601 formatter concurrency safety.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.3/OpenClaw-2026.2.3.zip" length="22530161" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="7eHUaQC6cx87HWbcaPh9T437+LqfE9VtQBf4p9JBjIyBrqGYxxp9KPvI5unEjg55j9j2djCXhseSMeyyRmvYBg=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>